So, when you're speaking with your tailor or maybe the rental place, where you're going to be renting your suit, or someone that is designing and creating something special for you, one thing to consider is different neck shapes that you have, which are going to kind of alter the shoulder style that your garment is going to be tailored in; your jacket specifically.
So, if you have a short neck, you're going to need a square shoulder, if you have a long neck, you're going to need more of a sloped shoulder and then if you just have a regular neck, you're going to need just a regular shoulder.
So, there's different ways to measure that, or there's different ways to kind of point out or notice and take into account, meaning what type of shoulder you want based on your neck, whatever neck you've been given.
And, all the necks are fine.
O.k.
so, most of it is going to be from here to here, same as we measured our shoulder seam; but I'll show it to you on paper, so you can kind of tell the difference and decide what you are because maybe you might be living with a long neck and you just don't realize that you have a long neck.
Alright, so let's look at the pages.
Alright, so here we are, shoulder style normal and that is, it's just like we measured before that point that goes from here to here.
And, then what we have is a sloping shoulder and as you can see I've showed you here, this is for like a longer neck, right.
If you have a longer neck, kind of bring your shoulders down like that and that is from here to there.
Within that, longer, longer meaning, meaning this way, you know.
And, then finally if you have like a short neck and you're stockier, it would be squarer from here to here.
Same thing.
So, maybe these diagrams will help you figure out whether you are a square neck, or excuse me, a square shoulder, a sloping shoulder or normal regular.